Wow, how shameful.
There's nothing more despicable in this world than black magic.
Was this person worth going to such lengths to revive?
It's no wonder Shiro's this angry about it.
The dangers of bringing someone back to life using such a method far outweigh the benefits.
For her sake, it would have been better if you had just let her...
Enough!
I get what you're trying to say, but please don't continue.
Forgive me.
Shiro, deep down, I'm sure you already know.
If it was you in that situation instead, you probably would have done the same thing.
I know that. It's just...
The way he acts really annoys me.
We've been eating monsters.
I think the red dragon was my favorite.
Look, look, it has a monster in it.
We used black magic, but you'll keep quiet about it, right, Shiro?
Anyway, I've no idea what's going through your head at any point.
And I doubt I ever will.
I can't help you.
Lyos! Send seat!
This is bad.
A herd of monsters is attacking the cooking group, and...
What did you do?
I told him everything that's happened up to now.
You what?
I honestly thought he would understand.
He's clearly the worst person to tell!
I know, right?
Is this all my fault?
Should I have followed Lyos instead of Senshi?
Don't be hard on yourself.
He's been through a lot, too, remember?
I have a lot of respect for him.
I've lost count of how many times he saved me during our adventures.
He told me about his homeland back when I only knew about this island and the town I was from.
Ever since I've known him, he's always been so wise and cool-headed.
But I managed to make him pretty upset today.
So I'm guessing what I did must have been terrible.
I'd hate for our friendship to end like this after all we've been through.
Harpies!
What a waste of time.
Athabi, follow the rest of us!
He told them everything, so now Shuro knows how we revive Falon.
What? That's why they're like that?
Shuro's extremely pissed off.
What should we do?
This gets to the surface. We're screwed.
I know, Chilchak, but even then...
Looks like the ninjas are handling things just fine.
So tell me, how many others know about it?
Four at the moment.
It's Shuro and two of his attendants.
And also that curly-haired guy.
Isn't he from that party that got wiped out by treasure bugs?
What are they doing here?
Who knows?
If anything, they're probably looking for the people who stole their loot and food.
We have to tell them what really happened!
How their treasure was actually treasure bugs and their food got all soggy and wasn't good anymore!
Idiot!
Knowing about the black magic is the bigger issue.
Shuro's upset, but that'll be fine.
His anger comes more from us putting Fallon in danger.
But I don't know how the others might feel.
By the way, back when you used that black magic, was there evidence left?
The magic circle should already be gone because of the cleaners.
But if my staff and Fallon's body were carefully inspected, we might be in some trouble.
We've got to burn your staff now, Marcel!
Wait!
Listen to me!
If we even get to the point where we're inspected, then it's already too late!
Hmm?
Ah!
There!
Look!
Wait.
The hell is that thing?
Well, it's...
not a heartbeat.
What?
What? No.
This can't be happening.
Phelan.
Is that...
No way.
What even is that?
It's the coolest thing I've ever seen.
But don't you think you got a little too greedy?
You have wings, feathers, and scales now.
Phelan!
Do you recognize who I am?
We're self-stoppish!
Phelan!
Hold!
Ready yourselves!
Lyos!
Shuro!
What do we do?
Give us orders!
Inutare!
Don't hurt her!
Restrain her instead!
You have to run, my lord.
Let's see.
What was it that he said?
Capture her, but don't hurt her.
How am I supposed to do that?
Can you do it, home?
Yeah.
All right.
Come on out.
Phelan!
That's...
an undine.
Are you the one who's controlling it?
Please tell her to fall back.
She's just a little confused, I promise.
Give it a rest already.
Don't you care how many people you're sacrificing
just to protect this one individual?
That's not even her anymore.
It's just a monster.
No!
We're really hey!
So it casts magic, too.
No!
That's enough!
We got to hide now!
Phelan.
Move aside!
And her sister, Alvin!
Oh!
all monsters are dangerous damn it kensuke you're just a monster after all
i'm sorry valon if i could have taken your place then i definitely would have
help me brother
valon the lungs get me
hurt
i'm dead
can you stand sorry i hesitated but you're absolutely right my sister's soul is more than likely being
controlled by the lord of the dungeon however if we kill her he's sure to show up here we need to
hurry and leave this place
felon
you feet
that spell is
everyone come to me now
you feet
you
she might return here let's take the wounded back to the barrier and as for the dead
uh i'm not sure
i can use revival magic
i can't get everyone know
do you want us to gather them
no please keep them where they are we can't waste even a single drop of their blood
the monster
everything's fine
it retreated
so
next is
hold on
i think you should go and resurrect her
why revive me next
i got the impression you're a pretty powerful spellcaster
so i assumed you could cast healing and revival spells
maybe you can help home with the rest since he can't get them all
and this was the least we could do to thank you
for everything
now i'm in your debt
you're likely looking for a different spell
but fine
let's finish this quickly
hey uh
if it's a simple revival spell
then i
no
you will not lay a finger on them
nor will i allow you to cast any more of that black magic
i
i wouldn't use that
then explain falon
what else could cause her to look like that
it's because of the dragon meat
paired up with your black magic
no way
impossible
that's not how the spell i used works
but
well
if it was black magic
then there must have been some kind of spell placed on the red dragon's soul
and once falon and the dragon's souls mixed together
she became the creature that just attacked us
sure
i'm taking marsil to the elves of the west
i cannot bring myself to kill that thing
but i also cannot let it run wild
so i want to at least be able to free her soul from the dungeon
so she can rest in peace
no please
the elves should know of a way to accomplish that
i want you to confess everything to the elves of the west
please stop this shiro
there has to be some other way that we can
no there isn't
are you even hearing yourself right now
another way you say
like what exactly
more of that black magic
what other monsters would you try to use with it
well tell me
if that's not it then what
you have a plan right
let's hear it
our plan is to defeat the mad mage
the red dragon was clearly following some kind of order it was given
and the only person who has the power to command that kind of creature is the mad mage
therefore we'll defeat him
and then rewrite that order
i honestly don't know how to do that kind of thing
but marcil should be able to
so i won't hand her over
stop fooling around laos
you started this with black magic
and you plan to use more to solve it
for once in your life
can you try to take this ship
sorry
it's true that i'm not particularly skilled in anything
and that you're stronger than most dungeon delvers
but i say this with absolute certainty
we've been eating three meals a day and getting sleep
which means we're able to take this more seriously than anyone else can
listen
we're going to take care of all this by defeating the mad mage
once we do we'll save falon
shuro you head back to the surface
go eat some food
take a bath
and get some rest
what's that
shut your mouth
don't go believing that you have this all figured out
if that's what you think
then i have a few thoughts of my own
what the
laos
you know what
for the longest time
i haven't been able to stand being anywhere near you
and it's because you're incredibly careless
thick-headed
and awkward
tell me more about other countries
oh you're gonna eat
i'll come too
hey
we're friends now aren't we
and you've never had ill intent
which made it more frustrating
i should just kill you right here
and hand marsil over to
why not say something sooner
what's the point in telling me now
if it was so hard to be around me
you sure told me back then so i knew
i tried to let you know in ways that most people would have picked up on
maybe you should get better at reading the room laos
how sure oh i'd finally made my very first friend on the island
did you expect me not to be excited about it
don't look at me like that
i hate it so much
that sincere look in your eyes while you shove your burdens onto everyone else
how was i supposed to know that
you don't ever talk
heck you don't even eat
what's the point did you even having a mouth at all
shut up you fool
you haven't even put in half the effort marsil does each day
i really don't think now's the time for this
what a childish squabble
i thought i had taught him better than this
if you include me there are seven dead
one heavily injured
and then three missing
the gnom and i could each revive half
but there isn't enough blood left
senshi
can you gather all the scattered ingredients
will do
if needed
i can cast a simple revival
no that will not be necessary
but you can help by healing the wounded and finding those who are missing
cast anything strange and i will cut you down
you see ishiro
guess who's stronger because they've been eating proper daily meals
it's me
c-curses
tasty
my lord
everyone has been revived
shall we make preparations to depart soon
no
prepare a returning spell
we're going back
are you sure my lord
we still haven't located ossipi
she'll find her way back if she wants to
we're deeply sorry my lord
we weren't strong enough
no
i know you all did your very best
thank you
i'm grateful you joined me
i'm returning to my country
i won't be coming back to this island
once on the surface
i'll report to the island lord
i see
i'd planned to return with felon
did she accept your proposal
i don't know
she asked for some time to think about it
so i've been waiting
i've never met a woman as fascinating as her
i love her voice
the way she thinks
her beautiful smile
the unfortunate thing is
i never told her exactly how i felt
i wish i would have told her sooner
what
he proposed out of nowhere
how bizarre
that's kinda just the world he lives in
don't you worry
i'll make sure to tell her for you
it's this side of you laios
that i envy
hey uh
you were a huge help in all this
no not really
my last attack was meaningless
no i was able to learn several things because of it
you were
each of the places you stabbed would have been fatal for a human
but that wasn't the case for my sister
which means either those areas don't have vital organs
or there are multiple of them
there are lots of monsters like basilisks
cerberus and psyllas that have multiple brains
it's common for chimera types
he looks so excited right now
guess he really does like monsters
is this knowledge his weapon
he says he'll defeat the mad mage
there are definitely people who come into the dungeon
who are more skilled than him
but they don't have the same motivation and knowledge he does
i think she hesitated
i honestly believe he can accomplish it
although
what's gonna happen after he does
whoever manages to defeat the mad mage
is said to obtain the entire country
but what if that means
that person becomes the next lord of the dungeon
what will this man do when he's in possession of this country
built by black magic and all these monsters
will he seal away this dungeon without a word
hey are you hungry
what even is this
it's samago yaki made from some harpy eggs
senshi found a few a little while ago
you said you were interested in monster cuisine right
you should try one
i do not want to eat that
what do i do to get myself out of this
maybe i could just kill him
kill
no i can't
thanks leos
of course
he'll do literally anything just to get on someone's good side
this guy's amazing
preparations for the returning spell are now complete
is anyone still injured
once we're on the surface
revival spells won't work
if i'm being honest
i'm fairly confident you'll perish even before reaching the mad mage
but if you do manage to survive
and you cannot return to the surface because of the black magic
ring the spell
it will resonate with its twin from anywhere
when it does
i'll send one of my people to help you flee to the east
don't die
thank you
leos
i'm glad that we met
i got so much out of talking to you
same for me
um
it's time to leave
you do actually remember my name don't you
hmm
of course i do
i'm glad
i hope you still remember it next time
well then
see ya
next time
let's go leos
there's no turning back anymore
i knew it
i had a feeling it was gonna turn out like this
and i was right
damn it
hey now let's settle down
sorry guys
things will work out somehow